So what is data visualization?
什么是数据可视化呢?
Well, data is stored on a computer.
数据存储在计算机中
But we want to work with the data, and so
而我们要处理数据
we need to get the data somehow out of the computer and into our heads.
我们就需要以某种方式将数据 从计算机输进我们的大脑
So we can think about the data.
从而可以对数据进行思考
So we can understand the data.
从而了解数据
So we can gain insight into what the data represents.
并深入理解数据的涵义
And so the best way we've found to do that is using visual communication.
我们发现最好的方法就是 通过视觉交流
And so data visualization is a high bandwidth connection between
数据可视化就是计算机和人脑 之间的高带宽链接
the computer and the human brain that transmits as efficiently as possible
以使数据尽可能有效地
the data from the computer and inserts it into our brains.
从计算机传入我们的大脑
And so here's a sample system, a typical visualization system,
这里有一个简单的例子 一个典型的可视化系统
that I've got diagrammed here.
我这里画了个图解
We have a scanner here that's going to acquire data.
我们这里有个扫描仪 它将用来摄取数据
In this case it's going to use a laser beam in order to scan.
即用激光束来扫描
The shape of this graduate student's head, and
被扫描的是这位研究生 头部的外形
then that data gets processed by the computer into geometry and
数据则由计算机处理成 几何形状和颜色
color, and then it gets displayed on this display screen.
然后显示在显示屏上
At this point we set up this visualization, this
在此刻我们设置了可视化
data visualization channel that's going to take this data from the display screen.
该数据可视化渠道将 从显示屏上获取数据
And inserted it into my brain through this perceptual channel.
然后通过人的知觉渠道 送入大脑
So, we get this visualization operation where I'm looking at the data,
所以我在看数据的时候 就是一个视觉化的行动
and it's going through my perceptual system,
它启用了我的知觉系统
going into my human memory and then I can start to think about it.
还有我的记忆 然后对其进行思考
In this case, there's some strange things happening with the laser scanning
在这里有些奇怪的事情发生在
here at the top of the students head.
这个学生头上的激光扫描中
And I want to try to understand why that's happening.
我将试图理解发生了什么
And so data visualization isn't just about seeing data.
所以数据视觉化不仅仅是 看到数据
It's about understanding data and being able to make decisions based on the data.
还包括对数据的理解和 采取相应的行动
And so another example of how data visualization has been useful.
再讲数据可视化有益的 另一个例子
Is when I discovered just as a university professor.
是我刚担任大学教授时发现的
So, students apply for
比如学生申请
graduate school at Computer Science at the University of Illinois, and
伊利诺伊大学计算机科学的 研究生
we have a webpage that they use to select faculty they might want to work with.
我们有一个网页 学生可用来选择 他们可能希望一起工作的教员
And so we say, pick out the three faculty members you'd like to work with,
比如说 选择三位你希望 一块工作的教员
and then we have drop down menus with all the faculty.
有一下拉菜单列举所有的教员
And students pick the faculty they want to work with, and then the students
学生就选择他们想一块工作的教员
having made that choice, that information is entered into a database.
学生所选的教员就存在 数据库里
And for each student applicant, we can see the faculty they might be interested in
对于每一位申请的学生 我们可看到他们感兴趣的教员
working with and we can start to get an idea for
我们也就可看出
each faculty member what students they would want to pick from.
对于每一位教员 哪些学生会选择他们
So, I wanted to plot to see how uniform this was across the faculty, and
所以我就想若显示出来 对于所有的老师 这种选择是否分布均匀
so I used a data visualization tool in order to do this and
为此 我就借助数据可视化工具
I came up with a standard bar chart.
我制作了一个标准的条形图
And, horizontally, these are basically the different faculty members.
横向坐标就是不同的教员
There's some faculty members are in our department, and some are affiliated
其中有些是我们系的 有些是附属的
with our department, and some get more students interested in working with them,
我们系的教员中 有的有多些感兴趣的学生
and some get fewer students working with them, and so
有的教员则少些
horizontally I've got the a faculty members here and vertically I'm plotting
这里横向坐标显示的是教员
the number of student that want to work with that faculty member.
纵向显示的是希望与 教员合作的学生人数
And so we've got some faculty members that are very popular and
我们看到有的教员很受欢迎
some that aren't very popular and again, some of the one's that aren't very
有的不那么受欢迎
popular are faculty that are affiliated with other departments.
有些不那么受欢迎的 是附属于别的系的
And students usually apply to work with them through other departments.
学生们通常是通过别的系 来申请与他们一块工作
And I've eliminated the faculty names here, just to avoid any embarrassment.
这里我没有标注教员的名字 以免引起难堪
So we've got this list and then I colour code it, the bar charts.
所以 有这一列数据 加上颜色编码 就生成了这样的条形图
This is a stacked bar chart.
这是堆积型条形图
I've colour coded the bar charts based on blue,
我给条形图使用颜色编码 以蓝色为初始色
if the faculty member was a students first choice.
以表示教员是学生的首选
Orange if the faculty member was the students second choice, and
橙色则表示是第二选择
green if the faculty member was the students third choice.
绿色表示是第三选择
And you might see something here,
你可能已看出点什么了
I certainly saw it when I first plotted this data, and
我起初绘制该数据图时 就发现了
that was that students were picking people in the first half of the alphabet.
那就是学生在字母表的前一半来选择教员
This is in alphabetical order.
这是按字母排序的
Students are picking faculty from the first part of the alphabet first,
学生优先选择的是字母表中 前一半的教员的名字
and they're picking people from the second half of the alphabet mostly last.
他们最后才会选择字母表中 后一半的教员的名字
And then the middle part of the alphabet, or I should say,
其次是位于字母表中间部分的名字 换句话说
they're picking second people uniformly across the alphabet and
他们的第二选择符合 在字母表中的均匀分布
what I discovered was that from this visualization,
从这个可视化数据中 我发现
was that students were picking faculty in alphabetical order.
学生们是根据字母顺序 来选择教员的
And having made that discovery from that visualization,
这个发现
I was able to work back into the system and
让我能够返回系统
figure out why students were picking faculty in alphabetical order.
审查为什么学生会按 字母表顺序来选择教员
And the reason was we had three pull down lists with all the faculty.
我们有三个包含所有教员名字的 下拉菜单
And so the students would go down the list and
因此学生会在在第一个下拉名单中
find the first faculty member they were interested in and click there.
选中他们第一个感兴趣的教授
They'd go down the list and pick the second faculty they were interested in and
他们会在第二个菜单中选择 他们第二感兴趣的教授
they would select that, and
他们会选择那个 并且
then they would find the third faculty member they were interested in and
最后他们会在第三个下拉菜单中 选择他们第三个感兴趣的教员
click that, and then that would go into the database, but when we were looking
最后这些选择会进入数据库
at the database, in order to evaluate what students might want to work with us.
但当我们在查看数据库的时候 为了评价哪个学生想和我们合作
We were assuming students were picking the faculty they wanted to work with first,
我们设想的是学生会在第一个菜单中 选择他们最先想合作的教员
as the first choice, and their second choice was second, and
第二个选择是他们第二想合作的
their third choice was third.
第三个选择是他们第三想合作的
When in fact, they were just finding three faculty members and
而实际上 他们只是按顺序选择了
picking them when they appeared in the list.
出现在名单中的教员
And so in this case data visualization helped us make a decision
在这个案例中 数据可视化帮助了我们的决策
that we wouldn't have been aware of otherwise.
如果没有它 我们不会意识到这个决策
And so that's a hallmark of data visualization is to provide
数据可视化的特点是让我们
insight into the data, and be able to use that insight in order
更深入了解数据 并用这个洞见
to make further decisions, further hypotheses to explore further.
做更高层次的决策 做能探索更多信息的假设
And so that's the kind of insight that I want to provide and
这就是我想通过这门课程 提供给你们的
the tools that I want to provide, to students in this course.
洞见和工具
And so we'll work through basically four weeks of materials on data visualization.
我们会通过四周的课程来学习数据可视化
The first week, we're just going to understand the platform for
第一周 我们会了解
data visualization.
数据可视化
Basically, how a computer displays data, and
也就是 计算机如何显示数据
then how the user perceives and processes it.
以及用户如何认知和处理数据
And so we'll spend most of the first week just studying the computer and
我们会用第一周的大部分时间 来学习计算机
studying the human.
来学习人
The second week, we'll introduce a few simple charts, bar charts and so on.
第二周 我们会介绍简单图表 比如柱状图等等
And more importantly, we'll look at the kinds of data that we want to display.
更重要的是 我们会看看 想要显示的数据的种类
That we want to visualize, and we'll make sure.
我们会确保
That we're using the proper chart for the proper kinds of data.
使用正确的图表来绘制正确类型的数据
And that the proper kinds of
正确类型的数据
data are being mapped to the correct elements of that chart.
被投射到图表中正确的元素上
And then we'll also talk about how to design charts effectively to
我们还会谈谈如何有效设计图表
convey that data.
来传达数据
In week three, we'll look at how to layout and
第三周 我们会看看如何放置和显示 其他数据
display other data, non numerical data, relational data.
非数字数据 关系数据
When you're data isn't necessarily going to be a number that
当你的数据不一定是个数字
will give you a height and a bar chart, but
让你能够给它在柱状图中通过高度来表示
is basically a relation that says item A is related to item B.
而是A物体与B物体有关系
How do we display that?
我们该如何显示这种关系?
How do we visualize that?
如何可视化?
How do we gain insight into that kind of data?
我们如何从这类数据中 获取洞见?
So we spend week three on
我们将在第三周
more looking at abstract data as opposed to numerical data.
谈谈这种抽象数据而不是数字数据
And then week four, we'll talk about visualizing data bases,
第四周，我们会谈谈可视化数据库
how to visualize the results of data mining.
如何对数据挖掘的结果进行可视化
And how to analyze the way we work, so
以及如何分析我们的工作方式
the visualization can provide us the insight into how do we make a decision.
使可视化能为我们提供决策所需要的洞察力
And so we'll talk about how to make a visualization dashboard that gives you
我们将讲到怎样制作一个图表盘
the information you need, in order to make an effective decision, and
提供你所想的信息 以帮助你
an informed decision.
做出有效和明智的决定
So I think it's useful to talk about what we won't be able to cover in these four
我也将提到这四周不会 涉及的内容
weeks.
相信会有所帮助
We're going to talk about abstract data visualization.
我们将讲到抽象数据可视化
I'm not going to be able to talk in much detail about specific tools used for
我不会讲关于可视化的 特定工具的太多细节，
visualization, or visualization tools for scientific visualization or
或者用于科学用途 的可视化工具
medical visualization, business data, business intelligence systems and so on.
或者用于医疗可视化 商业数据 商业智能系统等等
There's a number of tutorials.
有很多辅导课
And manuals for using specific packages and
以及使用手册 有关于关于使用特定程序包
we just won't have time to go into any one of them, but
我们没有时间来一一细讲 但是
i'll try to provide examples across those different applications.
我会尽可能提供 关于不同应用的例子
I'll be able to provide, provide a few design principles, but
我将会提供一些设计原理 但是
I won't be able to cover a full course on visual design for presentation and
我不能完全涵盖一个有关于 视觉显示的设计的完整课程 并且
so there are good courses on that.
这里也有一些 很好的课程
That you might take a look at, but, we'll just be looking at
你也许去看看 但是 我们将会
some very minimal design principles that are most effective for data visualization.
只关注于对数据可视化非常有用的 很基本的设计原理
And this will be an introduction to the topics of data visualization.
这是对数据可视化 这个主题的一个介绍
And data visualization can be a very deep subject.
数据可视化可以是 一门非常深奥的学科
And I won't be able to get into the details of visualization.
关于可视化 我不能讲的很细
Will be at sort of a high level of the different areas of visualization.
那会是可视化的不同领域的高级知识
But focusing on the important topics of visualization to
而集中在可视化的那些重要主题上
make any visualization successful, and to work well.
即使得可视化成功且方便使用
I'll try to provide pointers to tools, but again, not tutorials on how to use those
我会尽可能提到一些工具 但不是关于如何使用这些工具的辅导课
tools, and there'll be a couple of assignments in
并且 这里会有一些课后作业
the course, and programming can be used to complete those assignments and I encourage
以及可以使用编程来完成这些课后作业 我鼓励
you to program if you know how to do these assignments, but it's not required and
你使用编程来完成这些作业 但是这并不是必须的
I'll provide existing tools that you can use that you don't need to write a program
我会提供现有的可用的工具 这样你就不需要自己编写一个程序
in order to use to visualize your data in order to complete these assignments and
来用于可视化你的数据 来完成这些作业
in general to be able to visualize data.
和实现数据可视化
And finally, I'd like to
最后 我想
thank a few people that have been very helpful with putting this course together.
感谢一些曾经大力协助制作这门课程的师生
Eric Shaffer is a lecturer here at the University of Illinois.
Eric Shaffer是伊利诺伊大学 的讲师
And he's talked in one of the most recent scientific visualization classes we
并且他讲授了我们的最近的 一门可视化课程
had and he's provided some materials for me for this class from that.
他为我及这门课提供了一些资料
I've very grateful for his help on that.
我非常感谢他的帮助
Karrie Karahalios is also a professor of Computer Science here at the University of
Karrie Karahalios也是一名 伊利诺伊大学计算机系的教授
Illinois and she's taught social visualization classes,
她也教授社会学可视化课程
especially visualizing, kind of relational data in social situations and
特别是视觉化 类于社会环境中的关系数据
she's a world renowned expert on that area and
她是一个在这个领域 世界知名的专家
has provided me with a lot of resources and website links for
为我提供了很多资源和网站
tools to help with a variety of visualization methods.
关于各种可视化方法的工具
Mike Gleicher is a professor, a friend of mine at the University of Wisconsin.
Mike Gleicher 是一名威斯康星大学的 教授 我的朋友
We just completed a university wide data visualization course and had some nice
我们刚刚完成一门校内的数据可视化课程 并且有一些很好的
material there that he provided me that I've also been able to use in this course.
资料 我也会在这门课中用到
Donna Cox is a good friend of mine from the NCSA.
Donna Cox 是我的一个在（伊利诺伊大学） 国家超级电脑应用中心很好的朋友
Who taught me a lot of what I know about data visualization.
她教会了我很多关于数据可视化
And many other presentation visualization examples I'll be showing
我将会演示的许多可视化的例子
are her work from the National Center for
都是她在
Supercomputing Applications here at the University of Illinois.
伊利诺伊大学国家超级电脑应用中心的工作
And finally, Pat Hanrahan, professor at Stanford,
最后 Pat Hanrahan 斯坦福教授
has been very helpful and provided a lot of good advice and
一直非常地帮助 他提供了很多建议和
resources for data visualization, and I owe him my gratitude as well.
有关数据可视化的资源 我很感激
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community